Guide to the Stanford Ranches and Lands Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford ranches and lands records
1838-1896
SC0003
Stanford University
4 Linear feet
Abstracts of titles and transcripts of titles to various property holdings of Leland Stanford.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, President's Office, 1965.
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Scope and Content of Collection
Abstracts of titles and transcripts of titles to various property holdings of Leland Stanford, including the Palo Alto Stock Farm (Santa Clara Co.), the Vina Ranch (Tehama Co.), the Grindley Farm (Butler Co.), Mayfield Grange (Santa Clara Co.), the Gwinn Ranch (Contra Costa Co.), and San Francisco properties.
Access Terms
Gordon, George; Gridley Farm (Calif.); Gwinn Ranch (Calif.); Martin, Dennis; Mayfield Grange (Calif.); Palo Alto Stock Farm (Stanford, Calif.); Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893.; Vina Ranch (Calif.); San Francisco (Calif.)
Collection Contents
- Transcript of the title to "Dennis Martin Tract" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abstract of title to parts of the Ranchos Rincon de San Francisquito and Rinconada del Arroyo de San Francisquito (vol. 1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Abstract of title to parts of the Ranchos Rincon de San Francisquito and Rinconada del Arroyo de San Francisquito (vol. 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Abstract of title, Rancho "el Corte de Madera" (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Title of Rancho de San Francisquito Palo Alto (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Abstract of title to a portion of the Rancho de San Francisquito (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Abstract of title of part of Rancho Rincon de San Francisquito (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Abstract of title to parts of "Rancho el Corte de Madera" and San Mateo Cos. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ranchos San Francisquito Palo Alto and Rinconada del San Francisquito (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Title of the Rancho de San Francisquito Palo Alto (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Topographical map of the western portion of the Vina Ranch [oversize volume] (Box 3)
- Vina Ranch (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Vina Agency (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Gerke Ranch (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Berry Rancho (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Rancho San Francisquito (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Rancho de los Pulgas (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Bosquejo Rancho (Box 4, Folder 3)
- San Miguel Rancho (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Gridley Farm (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Gridley Ranch; building (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Tehama County Property (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Glenn County property (Box 4, Folder 8)
- George Gordon's Mayfield Grange (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Abstract of title of Eliza C. Tichenor to certain lands in Napa County, Hot Springs Township, Calif. From the Mexican Grant to Oct. 5, 1871 (includes Sam Brannan) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Folder of letters and map of Clistoga (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Mrs. Leland Stanford. Portions of block 93, western addition, n.s. corner of Van Ness and Pacific in San Francisco (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Abstract of title for lots in Township 24 N.R.I.E.M.D.M. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Abstract of Gridley Farm (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Abstract of Bosquejo Ranch and Gridley Farm (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Abstract of title #76 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Abstract of the San Miguel Rancho (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Stanford and Sunnyside Mort. R.M.'s (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Documents relating to San Francisco city or County (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Butte County Property (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Abstract and papers relating to Josiah Session (re lot at California and Powell Streets) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Rio de Los Molinos (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Ponce papers (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous, including Durham Ranch (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Gwinn - survey, 1888 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Gwinn Ranch (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Gwinn - Parcel #1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Gwinn - Parcel #2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Gwinn - Parcel #3 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Gwinn - Parcel #4 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Gwinn - Parcel #5 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Gwinn - Parcel #6, 7, 8 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Gwinn - miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Gridley Ranch abstract (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Translation of will of Maria de la Soledad de Ortega de Arguello dated, Nov. 14, 1862 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Mortgage from Timothy Paige to Job J. Felt covering part of Rancho el Corte de Madera, Mar. 23, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Deed form Job J. Felt to Timothy Paige for part of Rancho el Corte de Madera dated, Mar. 23, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Promissory note by Timothy Paige for $40,000 payable to Job J. Felt (with various receipts thereon signed by Thos. M. Quackenbush), dated, Mar. 23, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Assignment of mortgage from Job J. Felt to Thomas M. Quackenbush, dated, April 14, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Satisfaction of mortgage (from Timothy Paige to Job J. Felt and assigned to Thomas M. Quackenbush), dated, Mar. 3, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Abstract of title to portion of el Corte de Madera Rancho, San Mateo County, dated, May 5, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Abstract of Title and Certificate of Search, by Thomas H. Cordell re Peter Coutts Place on Rancho [Rincon] de San Francisquito; and Deed, Jeremiah Clark to Peter Coutts, Nov. 9, 1882, April 15, 1875 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Abstract of Title to Luis Antonio Arguello's portion of Rancho de las Pulgas, February 1883 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Abstract of title to various lands with cover name [Coon Rancho]; this is a search done for J. C. Gould by Edgar [Pomeroy]., May 9, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Copy of Henry P Coon will dated, Nov. 16, 1877 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Certification of G. H. Rice re McDonough title, May 7, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- List of filings in Probate of Will of Henry P. Coon, Dec. 1884-July 1886 (Box 8, Folder 10)